The key…
Cheia…
The key, the card, and the PIN code…
Cheia, cardul și codul…
The records of the experiment and the tape are in a safe deposit box.
Arhivele experimentului și caseta sunt într-o cutie de valori.
A tape?
O casetă?
The recording of the interview of a certain boy.
Înregistrarea interviului unui anume băiat.
He's the monster who brought destruction to Kinderheim 511.
E monstrul care a distrus Kinderheim 511.
PRAGUE POLICE STATION
SECȚIA DE POLIȚIE PRAGA
In here, please.
Aici, vă rog!
I brought him, Inspector Zeman.
L-am adus, dle inspector Zeman.
What?
Ce?
Inspector?
Dle inspector?
This is the man who first discovered the murder yesterday.
E omul care a descoperit crima ieri.
Ah, Mr. Grimmer.
Dl Grimmer.
I'm sorry to hold you overnight at the station.
Scuze că v-am ținut la secție peste noapte.
I dropped my nail clipper under my desk.
Am scăpat unghiera sub birou.
When you're as big as me, you can't help bumping into things.
Când ești mare ca mine, mereu te ciocnești de lucruri.
You're quite tall too.
Și dv. sunteți înalt.
Yes. I bump into things a lot too.
Da. Și eu mă ciocnesc mult.
I'm Zeman, the investigator in charge of this case.
Sunt Zeman, polițistul care se ocupă de caz.
I'm Grimmer.
Eu sunt Grimmer.
Please have a seat.
Luați loc!
I'm sorry, but I was cutting my nails so I'll finish up while we talk.
Îmi pare rău, îmi tăiam unghiile, termin cât vorbim.
Go ahead.
Vă rog!
My wife's so picky about my nails.
Soția e pretențioasă în privința unghiilor.
She doesn't like them too long.
Nu-i place să fie lungi.
She can't stand when they're white at the tips.
Nu suportă când sunt albe la vârf.
So I always end up cutting them too short.
Așa că mereu ajung să le tai prea scurt.
Yesterday must've been quite a shock.
Sigur ieri ați suferit un șoc.
Yes. I wasn't expecting to come across that.
Da. Nu mă așteptam să dau peste asta.
I heard you're a freelance journalist.
Am auzit că sunteți jurnalist independent.
Did you know about that man's past?
Știați despre trecutul acelui bărbat?
Mikhail Ivanovich Petrov.
Mihail Ivanovici Petrov.
His real name is Reinhart Biermann. He's German.
Numele lui adevărat e Reinhart Biermann. E german.
After German reunification, he was charged with many crimes, such as child abuse,
După unificarea Germaniei a fost acuzat de abuz asupra copiilor,
suppression of human rights, and illegal confinement.
încălcarea drepturilor omului și sechestrare.
He fled here to the Czech Republic after the Berlin Wall fell.
A fugit în Cehia după ce a căzut Zidul Berlinului.
He's charged with crimes in Germany,
A fost acuzat de infracțiuni în Germania,
but the Czech Republic police let him be and kept him under surveillance.
dar poliția din Cehia l-a lăsat în pace și l-a ținut sub supraveghere.
Under surveillance?
Sub supraveghere?
That's right. He's been associated with some unsavory elements
Da. A avut legătură cu unele elemente neplăcute
of the former Czechoslovakia secret police.
din fosta poliție secretă din Cehoslovacia.
Secret police?
Poliție secretă?
Surely you know of their horrific suppression
Cu siguranță știți de încălcarea oribilă
of free thought and speech in this country during the Cold War era.
a libertății de gândire și de exprimare din Războiul Rece.
They even provided weapons
Ei au oferit până și arme teroriștilor radicali de stânga din lume.
They were a despicable lot.
Erau niște gunoaie.
Since the split and democratization of the Czech Republic and Slovakia
Despărțirea Cehiei și Slovaciei și democratizarea lor
was relatively peaceful,
au fost relativ pașnice,
they were able to go underground without any serious condemnation.
așa că au reușit să dispară din peisaj fără să fie condamnați.
Petrov was working with those people.
Petrov lucra cu oamenii aceia.
He may have even sold the information he had to those people.
Poate le-a vândut informațiile pe care le avea.
See? I cut it too deep again.
Vedeți? Am tăiat-o prea adânc.
That's right. Did you see a woman at the scene?
Chiar așa. Ați văzut o femeie la fața locului?
A woman?
O femeie?
Apparently, the person who murdered Petrov was a young woman.
Se pare că o tânără l-a ucis pe Petrov.
She was quite beautiful too.
Și era destul de frumoasă.
The kids say they passed a woman in front of the house.
Copiii spun că au trecut pe lângă o femeie în fața casei.
But I didn't notice her.
Dar eu n-am observat-o.
I see.
Înțeleg.
Those kids,
Copiii aceia,
the ones that Mr. Petrov was caring for, what will happen to them?
de care avea grijă dl Petrov, ce se va întâmpla cu ei?
We're holding them at the station for now.
Îi ținem la secție deocamdată.
But starting today, they'll be sent in small groups to various orphanages.
Dar, începând de azi, vor fi trimiși la orfelinate.
Is that right?
Da?
It must be a lot of trouble for you too, getting caught up in this and everything.
Probabil v-a fost greu să fiți prins în situația asta.
It's okay.
E în regulă.
Incidentally, what did you want to speak to Petrov about?
Apropo, despre ce voiați să discutați cu Petrov?
It's just about the kinds of trouble you mentioned
Despre problemele menționate
that Mr. Petrov was once involved in.
în care a fost implicat dl Petrov.
Were you able to get anything out of him?
Ați obținut vreo informație?
No, before I could, he--
Nu, înainte să pot, a…
Perfect!
Perfect!
This ought to make my wife happy.
Soției mele îi vor plăcea.
Go ahead, you can leave now.
Puteți pleca.
I'm sorry we kept you here for so long.
Îmi pare rău că v-am ținut atât aici.
It's all right.
E în regulă.
Say…
Spuneți-mi…
Before he died,
înainte să moară,
did Mr. Petrov tell you anything in his dying breath?
v-a spus dl Petrov ceva cu ultima suflare?
No.
Nu.
You're Miloslav and Josef. All right, where's Thomas?
Sunteți Miloslav și Josef. Unde e Thomas?
Here.
Aici.
That's all three of you.
Sunteți toți trei.
Okay, hop on this van.
Bun, urcați aici!
Come on now. Hurry up and get in.
Hai! Urcați mai repede!
This next group of three is going to Vinohrady Child Welfare Center.
Următorul grup de trei va merge la Centrul de ajutor Vinohrady.
Honza, Antonin, Izzy.
Honza, Antonin, Izzy.
Here.
Aici.
This must be sad for you.
Sigur sunteți triști.
You all got along so well, but now you're being split up.
Vă înțelegeați și acum ei vă despart.
But even if you're split up, you'll still be under the same sky.
Dar, deși despărțiți, veți fi sub același cer.
Someday, you'll all be able to play soccer together again.
Într-o zi, veți putea juca fotbal împreună din nou.
Cheer up, Antonin.
Înveselește-te, Antonin!
You were the leader among them, right?
Tu erai liderul lor, nu?
Keep in touch with everyone by writing letters.
Ține legătura cu toți prin scrisori!
Doing that will keep everyone's spirits up.
Astfel, toți se vor bucura.
Okay.
Bine.
Good. That's the spirit.
Bun. Așa te vreau.
Oh, The Hotel Kafka.
Hotelul Kafka.
But first, I'd like to stop by the Procházka Bank.
Dar mai întâi vreau să trec pe la banca Procházka.
I'm sorry, but I don't speak much Czech.
Îmi pare rău, dar nu știu cehă prea bine.
Can you speak either German or English?
Poți vorbi germană sau engleză?
Why are you stopping? We're still not--
De ce oprești? Nu…
Hey, you could have at least warned me you were going to pick up other fares.
Trebuia să-mi spui că iei și pe alții.
NO ENTRY EXCEPT FOR ACCESS
INTRARE EXCLUSIV PENTRU ACCES
Excuse me, why have we left the city?
Scuze, de ce am ieșit din oraș?
My hotel is in the city.
Hotelul meu e în oraș.
The key.
Cheia.
What?
Ce?
What are you talking about?
Despre ce vorbești?
Well, well.
Ca să vezi!
Are you all right?
Ești bine?
I thought you might be in danger, so I followed you.
Am zis că poate ești în pericol, așa că te-am urmărit.
Are you hurt badly? Are you okay?
Ești rănit grav? Ești bine?
Inspector…
Dle inspector…
I'm pretty sure they were members of the former secret police I told you about.
Sigur erau membri ai poliției secrete despre care ți-am zis.
Did they demand anything from you?
Ți-au cerut ceva?
No, they didn't.
Nu.
I find it hard to believe they'd do this unless they wanted something.
Mi-e greu să cred că ar face asta dacă nu ar fi vrut ceva.
I mean it. They didn't want anything.
Serios. Nu voiau nimic.
I think you might be hiding something.
Cred că ascunzi ceva.
What? Why?
De ce?
Surely you must know of something. Why would they do something like this?
Sigur știi ceva. De ce ar face asta?
No, I don't know of anything.
Nu, nu știu nimic.
I guess you already got it out of the safe deposit box.
Cred că deja ai scos-o din cutia de valori.
The tape.
Caseta.
The audio tape.
Caseta audio.
They're looking for the roots.
Caută rădăcinile.
What do you mean? What "roots"?
Cine? Ce „rădăcini”?
The roots of the monster. They'll pay a bundle for it.
Rădăcinile monstrului. Vor plăti bine.
"Monster"?
„Monstru”?
Listening to the tape will tell us
Înregistrarea ne va spune
exactly where the monster's mother is here in the Czech Republic.
unde anume e mama monstrului în Cehia.
Hello? Inspector Zeman here.
Alo? Inspectorul Zeman.
Has the suspect in that supermarket robbery coughed up
Suspectul din jaful de la supermarket a spus
who his partner was?
cine era partenerul lui?
Is that right? Glad to hear that, Detective Suk.
Da? Mă bucur, detective Suk.
Me? I've got some other business to attend to.
Eu? Am niște treburi de rezolvat.
I think I'll make it back to the station in about an hour.
Cred că mă întorc la secție într-o oră.
Goodbye.
La revedere!
Better stop now or else he won't even be able to speak.
Oprește-te acum sau nu va mai putea vorbi.
He's probably about ready to talk now.
Probabil e gata să vorbească acum.
Where is the key?
Unde e cheia?
I have no idea what you're talking about.
N-am idee despre ce vorbești.
-Why you-- -Now, now. Hold on.
- Nenoro… - Stai așa!
Mr. Grimmer, it won't do you any good at all if you've hidden it.
Dle Grimmer, nu te ajută dacă ai ascuns-o.
Where is the safe deposit box key that Petrov gave you?
Unde e cheia de la cutia de valori a lui Petrov?
Like I said before, I can't tell you what I don't know.
Cum am mai zis, nu pot spune ce nu știu.
I see. So you want money, don't you?
Înțeleg. Deci vrei bani, nu?
Maybe I can help you out.
Te-aș putea ajuta.
How much would you like?
Cât vrei?
I may be a third-rate journalist, but I still earn enough to make a living.
Poate că sunt un amărât de jurnalist, dar mă descurc.
Mr. Grimmer…
Dle Grimmer…
Dear me, just look at how long your nails have gotten.
Uite ce ți-au crescut unghiile!
Didn't I tell you how much my wife hates that kind of thing?
Nu ți-am spus cât de mult urăște soția asta?
She doesn't like long fingernails.
Nu-i plac unghiile lungi.
Whoops! You shouldn't jerk around like that.
Ups! Nu te mai mișca!
I'll end up cutting them too short.
Altfel le tai din carne.
Where is it? Where's the key?
Unde e? Unde e cheia?
Where is it?
Unde e?
Even if you use that key to open the safe deposit box
Chiar dacă o folosești ca să deschizi cutia de valori
and retrieve the records and tape from it, you have no use for any of it.
și să iei caseta și arhivele, nu-ți vor fi de niciun folos.
The tape is useless unless it's in the hands of their organization.
Caseta e inutilă dacă nu e în mâinile organizației lor.
They need it to help them revive
Ei au nevoie de ea ca să readucă
the East Bloc nations to their former glory.
națiunile din Blocul de Est la gloria de odinioară.
That tape is a recording of just who the monster really is.
Acea casetă e o înregistrare a monstrului.
They need that monster, you see.
Au nevoie de monstrul ăla.
That monster is the one who can unite them all.
Acel monstru îi poate uni pe toți.
All those orphans from Kinderheim 511.
Toți orfanii de la Kinderheim 511.
He can assemble the orphans from Kinderheim 511 who were raised
Îi poate aduna pe orfanii de la Kinderheim 511,
to be the communist elite of former East Germany.
care să fie elita comunistă a fostei Germanii de Est.
There is no greater group of elites.
Ei sunt cei mai buni.
It's believed that the monster controlled everyone
Se crede că monstrul îi controla pe toți
in Kinderheim 511 and was the one who had it destroyed.
de la Kinderheim 511 și că el a fost cel care l-a distrus.
He's the only one who can bring together that squadron of elites.
E singurul care poate reuni escadrila de elite.
Okay, where's the key?
Bun, unde e cheia?
A squadron of elites, huh?
Un escadron de elite?
What's so funny?
Ce-i așa de amuzant?
What are you after?
Ce urmărești?
Is it money you want?
Vrei bani?
I'm a capitalist. I love money.
Sunt capitalist. Ador banii.
I simply want the key so I can sell it to those people.
Vreau cheia ca să le-o vând acelor oameni.
What the hell is your reason for doing this?
Tu ce motiv ai?
For social justice?
Dreptate socială?
There's no way you'd go this far for that kind of reason.
N-ai fi riscat atât doar pentru asta.
Who the hell are you?
Cine naiba ești?
You call yourself a journalist from the former East Bloc,
Ai zis că ești fost jurnalist din Blocul de Est,
but most of those people were intelligence agents.
dar cei mai mulți erau ofițeri de informații.
Some of the best were even spies.
Cei mai buni erau chiar spioni.
Who sent you here?
Cine te-a trimis aici?
Enough playing mister super spy.
Gata cu misterul de super-spion.
You think you're used to torture, huh?
Crezi că poți îndura tortura?
You're going to die, you know.
Să știi că vei muri.
Here's your last chance. Where's the key?
Ultima șansă. Unde e cheia?
Do you know about… the Magnificent Steiner?
Ai auzit de… Steiner Magnificul?
It was a cartoon that aired in West Germany in the 60s.
Era un desen animat difuzat în Germania de Vest în anii '60.
I was able to watch it even in East Berlin.
L-am văzut până și în Berlinul de Est.
The main character was someone who was usually a wimp.
Personajul principal era, de obicei, un tip fricos.
But whenever he was caught in a dangerous bind,
Dar, când era într-o situație periculoasă,
he'd always be saved by…
era mereu salvat…
his secret friend.
de prietenul lui secret.
But the main character didn't realize…
Dar personajul principal nu și-a dat seama…
that his secret friend was…
că prietenul lui secret era…
actually he himself.
de fapt, el însuși.
Whenever the main character found himself in a life-or-death situation,
Când acesta se afla într-o situație la limită,
he'd transform into the terrifying Magnificent Steiner.
se transforma în îngrozitorul Steiner Magnificul.
When the main character regained consciousness, the bad guys
Când personajul principal își venea în fire, tipii răi
would be beaten to a pulp.
erau înfrânți.
You'd better transform then.
Ai face bine să te transformi.
Come on, get on with your transformation.
Hai, să vedem cum te transformi!
Pour water on him.
Toarnă apă pe el!
You'll cough up its location soon. It's only a matter of time.
În curând, „scuipi” tu locația cheii.
Who the hell are you?
Tu cine naiba ești?
What?
Ce?
A woman came in…
A intrat o femeie…
There was a single shot.
A fost doar o împușcătură.
One of the dead men had been shot.
Unul dintre morți a fost împușcat.
But the other two dead men had no gunshot wounds.
Dar ceilalți doi nu aveau răni de glonț.
The Magnificent Steiner, huh?
Steiner Magnificul?
I've done it again.
Am făcut-o din nou.
Subtitle translation by: Bryan Athey
Subtitrarea: Carla Gîlcă